Welcome back.
Leading a project team comes with the
responsibility to create a psychologically
safe environment for
the people around you.
Through ethical and inclusive leadership,
you can create a team culture that
works for everyone and motivates the
people around you to do their best work.
In this video, you'll learn
the definitions of ethical and
inclusive leadership.
You'll also learn about the importance of
fostering a culture of respect, creating
equal opportunity to succeed, and ways to
invite and integrate diverse perspectives.
So what do ethical and
inclusive leadership entail in a team and
organization?
Let's start with ethical leadership.
Ethical leadership is a form of leadership
that promotes and values honesty,
justice, respect, community and integrity.
You promote ethical leadership by defining
and aligning values within your team and
demonstrating how adhering to those values
benefits the mission of the organization.
For an example of this, consider how work
culture has evolved in recent years.
Around the world, employees working for
organizations of all kinds have
been calling on their employers to
adopt ethical policy changes and
to state their positions
on current events.
Companies can demonstrate ethical
leadership by creating forums where
employees can raise their viewpoints,
be heard and
receive follow-ups from company
leaders on employee concerns.
Ethical leadership is closely
tied to inclusive leadership.
If ethical leadership's aim is to create
forums where employees' concerns can be
heard, inclusive leadership aims to put
what we've heard into action to create
an environment that encourages.
And empowers each and
every member of our community.
That in turn leads to more innovation and
better solutions.
Here's how we think about
inclusion here at Google.
Inclusive leadership is when everyone's
unique identity, background and
experiences are respected, valued and
integrated into how the team operates.
These differences improve
the team culture, collaboration,
innovation and output.
Inclusive leadership is related to
diversity in that diversity is the set of
differences each of us possesses,
whether visible or
invisible that gives us each a unique
perspective on the world and our work.
Inclusion is what the team does with that
diversity of thought and perspective.
At Google, we've identified three ways
that managers can lead inclusively.
These include fostering a culture
of respect, creating equal
opportunity to succeed and inviting and
integrating diverse perspectives.
To foster a culture of respect,
it's your job as a project manager to
serve as a role model, set the tone for
the team and take action when needed.
That means modeling the values
of your organization,
taking appropriate action
if misconduct occurs.
Creating an environment in which team
members feel comfortable speaking up
with concerns, and
recognizing team contributions regularly.
To create equal opportunity to succeed,
you should ensure that each person on
the team has access to the information and
resources they need to do their best work.
You do this through regular communication,
accessible documentation, and
regular check-ins with the team to listen,
share information, ask and
answer questions and provide support.
As a project manager,
you're in the perfect spot to identify
work that might be a good fit for
a person who really wants it, but
who shies away from asking for it.
Knowing an individual's aspirations will
help you highlight these opportunities.
Finally, to invite and
integrate diverse perspectives,
it's your role to cultivate a culture in
which each team member's perspective can
be openly shared, heard and
integrated into work related decisions.
You do this by creating a sense of
psychological safety on the team and
by inviting teammates to share
their thoughts, ideas and concerns,
regardless of their role or
rank on the team.
Developing ethical and
inclusive leadership skills
requires regular practice.
So whether you're leading
a project team of two, or 20, or
200, you should be diligent in building
up your inclusive leadership skill
set by creating an environment in which
your team feels safe, heard and valued.
You can do this by fostering a culture of
respect, creating equal opportunity to
succeed and inviting and
integrating diverse perspectives.
In the next lesson, we'll discuss the
fundamentals of influencing, as well as
some common mistakes that people make
when attempting to influence others.
Meet you in the next video.